Our lives are the sum of our choices.
Mission: Impossible - The Final Reckoning is a action, thriller,
adventure film directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
Ethan Hunt and team continue their search for the terrifying AI known as the Entity — which has infiltrated intelligence
networks all over the globe — with the world's governments and a mysterious ghost from Hunt's past on their trail.
Joined by new allies and armed with the means to shut the Entity down for good, Hunt is in a
race against time to prevent the world as we know it from changing forever.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
Grace, played by Hayley Atwell.
Luther Stickell, played by Ving Rhames.
Benji Dunn, played by Simon Pegg.
Gabriel, played by Esai Morales.
Paris, played by Pom Klementieff.
Mission: Impossible – The Final Reckoning is a 2025 American action spy film directed by
Christopher McQuarrie from a screenplay he co-wrote with Erik Jendresen.
It is the direct sequel to Mission: Impossible – Dead Reckoning Part One (2023)
and the eighth installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
The ensemble cast includes Tom Cruise (in his final portrayal of Ethan Hunt), Hayley
Atwell, Ving Rhames, Simon Pegg, Henry Czerny and Angela Bassett.
In the film, Hunt and his IMF team continue their mission to prevent the Entity, a
rogue artificial intelligence, from destroying all of humanity.
In January 2019, Cruise announced that the seventh and eighth Mission: Impossible films
would be shot back-to-back with McQuarrie co-writing and directing both films.
Plans for the eighth film changed in February 2021, with returning and new cast and crew members being announced soon after, including
Lorne Balfe, who composed the score for two other films in the series; Balfe was later replaced by Max Aruj and Alfie Godfrey.
Principal photography began in March 2022 but was suspended
in July 2023 due to the SAG-AFTRA strike.
Production resumed in March 2024 and concluded in November, with filming
locations including England, Malta, South Africa, and Norway.
Originally subtitled Dead Reckoning Part Two, the film
changed its subtitle in November 2024.
With a $300–400 million budget, The Final Reckoning is
one of the most expensive films ever made.
The Final Reckoning had its world premiere in Tokyo on May 5, 2025, was screened out of competition at the 78th Cannes
Film Festival on May 14, and was theatrically released in the United States on May 23 by Paramount Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $598.8 million
worldwide, while also having the largest opening weekend of the franchise.
It was the last film co-produced by Paramount and Skydance as
separate entities before they merged on August 7, 2025.
The film explores themes of mask, artificial
intelligence (a.i.), diving, submarine, espionage.
The tone is intense.